<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Aditya&#39;s Corner 🚀</title>
    <link>https://adityajoshi.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Aditya&#39;s Corner 🚀</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Copyright notice</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 16:45:28 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://adityajoshi.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Openbox Power menu setup</title>
      <link>https://adityajoshi.github.io/posts/openbox_power_menu_setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 16:45:28 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adityajoshi.github.io/posts/openbox_power_menu_setup/</guid>
      <description>Adding Shutdown, Restart, Suspend, and Hibernate Options in Openbox Menu If you&amp;rsquo;re using Openbox as your window manager and want quick access to power options like Shutdown, Restart, Suspend, and Hibernate, modifying the menu.xml file is a simple and effective approach.&#xA;📌 Steps to Add Power Options Locate your menu.xml file&#xA;Typically found at:&#xA;~/.config/openbox/menu.xml If it&amp;rsquo;s not there, check in /etc/xdg/openbox/menu.xml.&#xA;Edit the File&#xA;Open it in your favorite text editor:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>git commands to manage work</title>
      <link>https://adityajoshi.github.io/posts/git_commands_to_manage_work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 08:26:21 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adityajoshi.github.io/posts/git_commands_to_manage_work/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s very important when you are workin on big feature (which takes more than a day to complete) to take out latest code from target branch ( the one where I wish to merge my code eventually ) and merge in current working branch at-least once a day. For past few years I have been used to IntelliJ/PyCharm IDE which has spoiled me with it&amp;rsquo;s UI options so much that at times I find it hard to re-collect underlying git command.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle REGEXP_REPLACE</title>
      <link>https://adityajoshi.github.io/posts/oracle_regexp_replace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 09:21:08 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adityajoshi.github.io/posts/oracle_regexp_replace/</guid>
      <description>This post is to remind myself power of Oracle REGEXP_REPLACE. At time I forget how this in-build function can be used instead of writing a code!&#xA;Few examples: Below will replace remove digits.&#xA;WITH strings AS ( SELECT &amp;#39;abc123&amp;#39; s FROM dual union all SELECT &amp;#39;123abc&amp;#39; s FROM dual union all SELECT &amp;#39;a1b2c3&amp;#39; s FROM dual ) SELECT s &amp;#34;STRING&amp;#34;, regexp_replace(s, &amp;#39;[0-9]&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;&amp;#39;) &amp;#34;MODIFIED_STRING&amp;#34; FROM strings Output:&#xA;STRING MODIFIED_STRING abc123 abc 123abc abc a1b2c3 abc Convert multiple spaces to single space.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Importance of brackets around variables in Makefile</title>
      <link>https://adityajoshi.github.io/posts/brackets_in_makefile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:35:57 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adityajoshi.github.io/posts/brackets_in_makefile/</guid>
      <description>Brackets make it possible for make command to identify defined variable. Without brackets ( round or curly ) make command will only consider the very next character after &amp;ldquo;$&amp;rdquo; sign as variable, leaving remainting characters of the actual word.&#xA;Consider below Makefile. Remember it&amp;rsquo;s Makefile so indentation is TAB.&#xA;all: @echo &amp;#34;Building all targets...&amp;#34; target1: VAR = Value_for_target1 target1: @echo &amp;#34;Building target1 with VAR set to $(VAR)&amp;#34; target2: VAR = Value_for_target2 target2: @echo &amp;#34;Building target2 with VAR set to $(VAR)&amp;#34; and if you run&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Useful commands and scripts</title>
      <link>https://adityajoshi.github.io/posts/useful_commands_scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 08:36:08 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adityajoshi.github.io/posts/useful_commands_scripts/</guid>
      <description>TAR Command to archive just the given folder ( no absolute paths )&#xA;tar -cvf file_name.tar -C ~/ folder_to_be_archived -C option will make tar command to change it&amp;rsquo;s directory from whereever it is to ~/ (home path)&#xA;To install ncurses lib on fedora&#xA;sudo dnf install ncurses-devel-6.4-7.20230520.fc39.x86_64 Note - Hit tab after nucrses-devel. It will pick up available version.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mastering yt-dlp</title>
      <link>https://adityajoshi.github.io/posts/learn_yt_dlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 06:38:44 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adityajoshi.github.io/posts/learn_yt_dlp/</guid>
      <description>In the age of online media consumption, YouTube has become an indispensable platform for video content. However, there are times when you want to save a video for offline viewing or archival purposes. That&amp;rsquo;s where yt-dlp comes into play. yt-dlp is an enhanced version of the popular YouTube video downloader, youtube-dl, with added features and improvements. In this blog post, we will explore how to use yt-dlp to download YouTube videos in various formats.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Useful docker commands</title>
      <link>https://adityajoshi.github.io/posts/docker_commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 20:30:14 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adityajoshi.github.io/posts/docker_commands/</guid>
      <description> Fetch and run docker image docker run -it python:3.9 Build docker image using Dockerfile in current directory. docker build -t test:pandas . This will make image based on your docker file and tag it with name test:pandas So that you can run same as docker run -it test:pandas </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Dockerfile</title>
      <link>https://adityajoshi.github.io/posts/docker_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 20:39:18 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adityajoshi.github.io/posts/docker_intro/</guid>
      <description>A Dockerfile is a text document that contains all the commands a user could call on the command line to assemble an image.&#xA;In otherwords, it will have commands that you want to run to build your docker image.&#xA;Example file -&#xA;# This image is based on python:3.9 docker image from python:3.9 # install pandas in the base image. RUN pip install pandas # Make the entrypoint for this image as bash.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Docker setup on mx linux</title>
      <link>https://adityajoshi.github.io/posts/docker_in_mxlinux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 18:17:48 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adityajoshi.github.io/posts/docker_in_mxlinux/</guid>
      <description>Steps to setup docker on MX Linux.&#xA;Follow instructions provided in this link for debian distro. Run sudo groupadd docker Then sudo usermod -aG docker $USER Install apparmor if not already. sudo apt install apparmor Restart services. sudo service apparmor restart and sudo service docker restart Run docker run hello-world =&amp;gt; this should tell you whether you have installed properly or not. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configure xdg-open for a File or URL</title>
      <link>https://adityajoshi.github.io/posts/configure_xdg_open/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 08:45:13 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adityajoshi.github.io/posts/configure_xdg_open/</guid>
      <description>If you are using linux machine chances are that you are already using xdg-open.&#xA;xdg-open is a utility used by system to open a file or URL in the user&amp;rsquo;s preferred application.&#xA;To run a specific program for a given type of file or URL all you have to do is create a .dekstop file and configure so that xdg-open can run mentioned program for you.&#xA;To do that create first a desktop file.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solve Git submodule Update Error</title>
      <link>https://adityajoshi.github.io/posts/git_submodule_error/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 23:14:34 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adityajoshi.github.io/posts/git_submodule_error/</guid>
      <description>At times you will maintain or use a git repo which contains another repo as a submodule. Sometimes when you update or add this submodule again you may end up error like this.&#xA;&amp;#39;main_repo/sub_repo&amp;#39; already exists in the index. To fix this run below command and try adding submodule again.&#xA;git rm -r --cached main_repo/sub_repo git submodule add --force -b main {repo_url} {folder_to_use_for_sub_repo} </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Change Git Remote URL via terminal</title>
      <link>https://adityajoshi.github.io/posts/git_change_remote_url/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 12:42:54 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adityajoshi.github.io/posts/git_change_remote_url/</guid>
      <description>I used to clone github repositories with https link. We could use our github credentials with Git command line.&#xA;However as of August 21, Github has removed support for using your account password from Git command line.&#xA;That means you either need to generate Personal Access Tokens or configure repo with ssh keys.&#xA;I prefer 2nd option and that would mean that I need to change remote url in my checkout repo.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reduce Thinkpad&#39;s trackpoint sluggishness on Linux</title>
      <link>https://adityajoshi.github.io/posts/thinkpad_trackpoint_linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 22:58:11 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adityajoshi.github.io/posts/thinkpad_trackpoint_linux/</guid>
      <description>If you have installed Linux on a Thinkpad with X11 and feel trackpoint is sluggish to work with then give below config a try. Ideally this should work on any debian based linux distro.&#xA;Open a terminal and copy below snippet.&#xA;id=`xinput | grep -ie &amp;#34;TrackPoint&amp;#34; | awk &amp;#39;{ print $6 }&amp;#39; | awk &amp;#39;BEGIN{FS=&amp;#34;=&amp;#34;} {print $2}&amp;#39;` xinput set-prop $id &amp;#34;Coordinate Transformation Matrix&amp;#34; 6 0 0 0 6 0 0 0 1 What we are doing here is chaning X and Y sensitivities (set to 6) where both are 1 by default.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create Oracle database in Oracle Free Tier Cloud</title>
      <link>https://adityajoshi.github.io/posts/oracle_instance_in_oci/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 09:07:23 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://adityajoshi.github.io/posts/oracle_instance_in_oci/</guid>
      <description>If you want to work on oracle db but don&amp;rsquo;t want to do setup or worry about performance of it in your machine then I would recommend you to try oracle ATP database in cloud. Setting up new database and connecting with your trusty Oracle SQL Developer IDE is fairly simple. This guide will walk you through same.&#xA;Prerequisite : You will need Oracle Cloud Free Tier Account to get started.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
